Fady Faheem

Fort Worth, TX (682) 717-6391

<u>contact@fadyfaheem.com</u> - E-Portfolio: fadyfaheem.com

Languages: English & Arabic

A creative and problem-solving **software developer** with over 4+ years of delivering high-end software and frontend engineering services to high-value clients. Strong passion for both developing applications and websites with great user experiences. Currently working on difficult programming problems and learning from real-world challenges.

My skills include the following:

- HTML, CSS
- React.JS
- Swift
- C# and Unity

- Java and JavaScript
- Python
- Team Building / Leadership
- Verbal/Written Communications
- Agile/Scrum Management
- Quick Learner
- Drives Results
- Team Player

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bell Textron Inc. Arlington, TX

Media-IT Support Admin / Developer – Full Time

July 2024 - Present

- Designed and implemented Flask Python APIs to integrate data ingestion for Bell Aircraft systems (Collins, Garmin, and etc...)
- Worked with multiple front-end frameworks building UI in React.JS, Svelte, Maui, and or Angular.
- Created and designed Unity applications to help streamline processes, such as XML courseware editing, and building Crew alerting system (CAS) in Unity game engine.
- 3D modelled and printed custom parts to support training in both mechanical and in-flight applications.
- Maintained over 300+ machines for classroom usage, including building a synchronization tool in C# to keep all instructor machines with up-to-date courseware.
- Developed and maintained positive relationships and contracts with internal and external customers and industry leaders.

Bell Textron Inc. Arlington, TX

Training Support Admin / Developer – Full Time

July 2023 - July 2024

- Created and maintained pilot scheduling applications both on web and native mobile platforms.
- Wrote Excel VBA (Visual Basic for Applications) to forecast revenue, generate reports, and streamline administrative duties.
- Established a system to monitor, control, and maintain tools within the company, lowering tool loss by
 4%
- Monitored and updated Kubernetes deployments for excessive complexity, and workflow operation, and uptime.

Bell Textron Inc. Arlington, TX

IT Software Intern / Software Developer Co-Op – Full Time

Sep 2022 – July 2023

 Created and designed a comprehensive master plan to efficiently develop software solutions over two years, effectively streamlining digital access

EDUCATION